<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random blogging</title>
    <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Random blogging</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 23:16:29 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tintrongnguyen.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Obsession</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/blog/obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 23:16:29 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/blog/obsession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right off the bat, I apologize for this long and unexpected email. I like to write down and arrange everything, something I can&amp;rsquo;t do in face to face encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you knew, I am a software engineer. But it seems that I also have genuine passion toward creative creation in general. Say it cheesy but I feel like making something that I hope would carry a mission to change, even smallest as possible, something fundamental even, on the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In specifics, writing screenplay catches my attention recently. I see the potential in crafting dialogues and scenes, how it can transform into movies. Movies that tell stories with powerful devices to transform audience into better versions of themselves. I hope my work would spark a little thought of kindness in people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But painfully, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like starting to work on this. I dont have a drive to move me forward. Clouds of doubts shadows the writing notebook. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where this writing path would lead me to. After all it&amp;rsquo;s the creative product making that I am interested in, and this can happen in a lot of other fields, even at my current career as establishing a tech startup. Why jump into this high risk playground?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, another thing I like doing is playing football. I play every Monday and Thursday. Those are the weekdays I look forward to. Honestly, deep down, there is a call for professional football. And it is a shame that I became aware of this a bit too late. Kids would aim to go pro in football when they turn 10. Me,  a 22 years old dude with height issue, questioning about the ridiculous chances I might have in this career. But I can imagine, it would be a definitively joyful journey. Playing football everyweek gives me a glimpse of my distant yet surely happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my plan is to cross the professional football path and go for something else sustainable to provide for my regular football hobby. It feels like chopping one finger off and comforting yourself at the same time as you have nine left. To me, it&amp;rsquo;s okay as long as I am on the field. This fact describes my drives for the sport to some degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the problem. I am obsessed with this game. It gives me trouble sleeping as I would spend hours nightly thinking about the whatifs in the previous football match. What I could&amp;rsquo;ve done. I subconsciously recall the details of my touches with the ball and how I handled each situation. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but drowning in the stream of thougths about my performance. I am obsessed with this game. Eyes closed but my body still reacts to the moves I wished I would&amp;rsquo;ve played.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d experienced this before. It was when I play DotA 2 for hours before going to sleep in 3 am only because of morning school. Still, lying on the bed doesnt make me sleepy. I keep thinking about the choices, actions I made in the past games. Sometimes even worse, I open the laptop and browse to the match statistics site, only to check the numbers and winrate. Going pro in DotA 2 sometimes even pass by  to say hello and disappears right away. Lucky I still had some senses left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The behavior I presented is the kind I want for my serious work. I want to be hypnotized like that in my writing game. Something is missing. Is there a logical explanation for this? Or it is just simple that everyone would fall into a blackhole created by themselves if they overspend time into something? Is it just some people would simply prefer games, playful, relaxing activities over &amp;ldquo;creative work&amp;rdquo;? What can I do to feel the way I want to feel about my dream?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tin NG&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P/s: I wrote this on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtleties</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/blog/subtleties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 02:40:55 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/blog/subtleties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyday I travel to work by a 15 years old motorbike. Earphone plugged, helmet buckled and I&amp;rsquo;m ready to roll. The feeling of igniting this rusty engine is autonomous and comforting. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s the only thing I look forward of a new day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I easily pass through the familiar commute condensed with commuters. I think of my driving as a ninja, soundless. In Vietnam, people mostly use the honk as a device to rudely ask for a way. So, interestingly, frustration is also a byproduct to make progress. For me personally, I don&amp;rsquo;t touch the button because I despise its annoying sound. I simply cant trade a good mood to go a little faster, its not even close. This little choice adds in my subtleties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stop by the regular breakfast store and buy a small pack of chicken sticky rice. I take off my sunglasses as an act of politeness, checkout and put it back on. Even I am the person using the service, never once a thank you sealed in a subtle smile is absent. I carry on my journey, leaving behind nothing but a joyful store owner. The tiny gestures embedded in my social encounter adds in my subtleties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally arrived at the workplace, I have to park my bike first. The parking service here is very amusing. Every company rent office here have to pay parking fee prior every month, but they don&amp;rsquo;t have or don&amp;rsquo;t care to create the database of employees. Therefore, they have to ask every person coming in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 thousand Dong, pls&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, you work here? Ok, go ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every single morning, I have this mundane conversation with a young dude trying to be opportunist to have an extra 5.000 Dong. The irony is that if you pay the ticket once and the next time don&amp;rsquo;t, accusations for lying are gonna be tossed around. What is interesting is that he doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to believe my identity but always let me through with a cloud of doubt over his head. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to get rid of this awkward situation once and for all. By repeating some actions when interacting with him, I can make him remember me as a member of this building. First, I take off my sunglasses, unplugged one of my earbuds. Then I say aloud my bike registration number:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5327&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not forget the smiled thank-you, I take the parking ticket and bounce right away as if I&amp;rsquo;m a regular customer, which I am indeed. I&amp;rsquo;ve been  practicing this scheme for a week, hoping one day my subtleties sink in and he accept me through the gate. The one that I&amp;rsquo;m ironically privileged of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is your subtleties?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 months a sailor</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/blog/6-months-a-sailor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 02:40:55 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/blog/6-months-a-sailor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while I&amp;rsquo;m not publishing anything. My small little blog seems a little dusty I feel sticky
typing this new post. The past 6 months was wild, filled with events shall never fade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished my thesis project and successfully defended it against a board. A+ was a fair trade for the hardship I&amp;rsquo;d been
enduring for half a year. My graduation thesis was about Digital Signal Processing, a territory I&amp;rsquo;d never set foot on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first it was uncomfortable since even with the sincere guidance from Mr. Nhut, my thesis instructor, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get a
gasp of what to do. The Fourier series and all kind of transforms did their best morphing me into a DSP research student,
but all failed. That was when I know this academic journey wasn&amp;rsquo;t for me and I needed a different approach. It&amp;rsquo;s not
sticks and stones that can win this thesis battle, especially this engineering project. I needed brute force. Guns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thesis boat had sailed but stranded. The worried instructor helplessly turned to me, his first research student,
and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re getting overpowered. You should swim back to land. I&amp;rsquo;ll defend those academica monsters for ya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hesitated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But your Fourier cannons won&amp;rsquo;t last long, you could di&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He suddenly grabbed my shoulder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to me son, it&amp;rsquo;s my fault bringing you on this wrong fight. But you deserve another chance to battle the right one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now leave!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I swam back the the land, where I could be calm and thinking clearly. Actually, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think a bit. I went straight
into coding mode, applying my programming kung-fu to illustrate the way Fourier transforms work. After 1 week, I came back
the ship with a Golang AK47 rifle that left the captain in awe.
With this awesome firepower, the project was basically done. A good understanding
of audio and the methods to manipulate it is crucial. It gave me the confidence and intuition to read papers and
implement them. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before I slain the thesis with my rifle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I was wrong. In research field, it&amp;rsquo;s not experimenting but writing that drives you crazy. I spent 1 month completing
the project, and 5 months to present it in a scientific way. And a rifle was not the right weapon, again. I needed
something subtle but lethal when executed right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The captain shouted out loud:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pirates are coming! Prepare to melee combat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He turned to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your magic won&amp;rsquo;t work now, son. You better go back, I&amp;rsquo;ll fight them for ya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt bad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me look for more Go packages. I can stil&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brave heart slapped me in the face:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to me nerd! There&amp;rsquo;s no open source copy-paste that can save you now. But you have to be alive to save us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now go go go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back and apprenticed a blacksmith undercover sword master. He taught me the art of sword fighting and gave the
legendary sword LaTex to fight the pirates. So again, I rushed back to the fleeing ship to rescue my beloved captain and
crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was mayhem. I used LaTex to write my little thesis, it&amp;rsquo;s
an okay choice. Yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have beautiful format, professional looking document, but who cares, really. After
scrapping the brain for ideas, how to present them, I had to go deeper in hell writing LaTex in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sublimetext.com/&#34;&gt;SublimeText&lt;/a&gt;. And guess what,
when a syntax or semantic error pops up, only God knows where it crashes your document. Lesson learnt. Only trust LaTex
when time is out of the equation, otherwise Google Docs is your best bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tough times never last, only tough people do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After writing is printing, of course. Every details had to be the same as it is required. A word of advice, prepare the
layout and format of the cover as many printing firms don&amp;rsquo;t have a ready template. I recommend the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inlamson.com.vn/&#34;&gt;Lam Son&lt;/a&gt; photocopy and printing shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the day of reckoning, when I had to defend against a group of elite professors and doctors. I was all in for the
technical aspect of my project. By that, I pushed the demo project to the internet, even the slides are made in a very
geeky way. The objective was to showcase the strength of engineering, though until now I doubt any member of the board
realized that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the demo, I chose the popular song at that point &lt;code&gt;We don&#39;t talk anymore&lt;/code&gt; to perform audio watermarking. It was a
reckless move I reckon. But fortunately it yielded warming results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 6 months doing research, I can firmly say that, I&amp;rsquo;d never do this again, ever. To be fair, it was a nice to have
and one time only experience, especially when I&amp;rsquo;m at the gate of adulthood. The returned attributes are invaluable for
whom intend to apply for post grad school. However, it&amp;rsquo;s not for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank Mr. Minh-Nhut Ngo, my instructor, for this wonderful tryout in the DSP field. It gave me nightmares
sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to express gratitude towards the boards, whose kind but precise comments had enhanced my thesis significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last but not least, I&amp;rsquo;d like to stop here to go out with my family.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The acid-free letter</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/blog/the-acid-free-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 23:16:29 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/blog/the-acid-free-letter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hi Education, my lady&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s surprising to realize that we&amp;rsquo;ve known each other for a really long time, yet this is the first time we talk, like really? Our first met was so humble that I hardly recognize you from the images.
You was so complicated yet so beautiful. The way you could instantly tell whether
a number is prime was so attractive that guys keep giving
you arbitrary numbers just to hear your voice. I was in love, blindly. As time passes, I tried so
hard to befriend with you. Make friend with the librarian, apprentice the most evil profs, kill the last light, I&amp;rsquo;ve done it all.
Fortunately, it was okay, for a while. Until one day, your complexity hit me like a train. I knew that train would
come one day, but damn &amp;hellip; that algorithm.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/dFGKLIk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;leo&#34; /&gt;
You changed so fast I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even look you in the eyes, your beautiful
eyes. Even thinking about you horrified me, I was suffocated as your big Os slowly appearing in my mind. Seeing you hanging
out with other guys amplified the pain inside even more. Soon, my endurance maxed out and I dropped. You were my first, one-sided love,
yet I cowardly turned tail and ran. How miserable is that? I let the gods decide. Today, I am writing this not to pledge empathy but to seek redemption for my own mistake.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that I dwell in the past or something, but this is a good occasion for me to do this.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/oX5RRGN.gif&#34; alt=&#34;hart&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As time passes, I entered university to be even more miserable. Like wtf? We went to the same school, again. I was drowning in
the battles inside my own head. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to hurt your parents feelings as they asked me to take care of you, but on the other hand I would have to lie to myself doing so because frankly, I disgust you to my core. I thought you would become mature with uni, but no, somehow you leave your beauty back in high school, you changed. At uni, you turn yourself into a joke, and I got news for you, it was not funny. The way I saw it, you and your friends was a big-ass joke walking around in the uni, while everyone else pretend to attentively listen and laugh. &amp;ldquo;Ha ha ha&amp;rdquo;. You guys made me sick. Ironically, doctors aren&amp;rsquo;t supposed to make me sick, but your friends did. The worst part is I was trapped in this rat race. In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t notice, your parents gave me money, a lot of money, just to look after you. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t give up, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bad thing. Couple months passed, I stopped whining and accepted the rules. I lied to myself playing your parents game, while try my best govern the rage inside. What&amp;rsquo;s worse than 2 faces liar? I let the gods decide.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am sorry for putting all over you like this, I truly am. I know now, it is not entirely because of you that I become so toxic towards love matters. I&amp;rsquo;ve been single for 3 years, and it just recently that I open myself more than often. I&amp;rsquo;d met this girl, her name is W. Right now, dating with her make me feel good about myself, I&amp;rsquo;ll see how this goes. More importantly, I know now that your parents is the reason why we couldn&amp;rsquo;t be together, it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely your fault. But I can&amp;rsquo;t blame them too, parents always wish the best for their child, right? Okay, the letter&amp;rsquo;s getting long now, I better pause and reserve the good stuff for later. This is my first letter for you, there would be more, when the time comes. I am looking forward to your reply.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best regards,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;T&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P/s: How&amp;rsquo;s you parents doing? Is Mr. Government still lives alone? Send my regards for your parents,okay? You should take better care of them, I heard there&amp;rsquo;s a virus called democracy going around.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First bricks</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/blog/first-bricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 18:57:44 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/blog/first-bricks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The reasons why I created this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-want-to-write&#34;&gt;I want to write.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can feel the urge to write down something that clicks people. I want to do it. And I
doing it right now. It is one of the main reasons why I&amp;rsquo;m combining my limited vocabularies
to create something barely works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/TwRKVsd.gif&#34; alt=&#34;joker&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is about eliminating poor choice of words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-want-to-record-my-mind&#34;&gt;I want to record my mind.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things happend in a day and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to recall everything. So it&amp;rsquo;s better to have a place where
you can filter the good stuff and write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create stories, we need materials. It&amp;rsquo;s in everyday life if we know where to look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-idea-of-having-something-your-own-is-liberating&#34;&gt;The idea of having something your own is liberating.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Tin, a software engineer based in Saigon, Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love building software and products in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m bored, reading and writing are my options to escape reality. Like computers, right? I/O operations are the most common activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently work at &lt;a href=&#34;http://floatingcube.com&#34;&gt;Floating Cube Studios&lt;/a&gt;, also based in Saigon. We develop point of sale products and packages for small to middle size clients in Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t call myself a writer, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to fit in the writing habit.
There&amp;rsquo;s something about crafting sentences that lures me into creating this blog and start putting my thoughts online.
I personally think the choice of words is art.
Strangely, I can&amp;rsquo;t write in my mother tongue, yet, the feeling of cringing keeps striking me.
It&amp;rsquo;s something I definitely should work on, as this practice of literacy possibly be my main activity in the next 10 years.
And writing in English is not a good approach for a non-native speaker, in a country that doesn&amp;rsquo;t speak the language.
At the moment, I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying the freedom of burden and write whatever I want.
But in the long run, screenwriting is what I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a writer of any kind and located in Saigon, drop me a buzz and I buy you a drink! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/code/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/contact/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about removing this page. There are links to my &lt;em&gt;boring&lt;/em&gt; social life up there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>