<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fixed on Random blogging</title>
    <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/fixed/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fixed on Random blogging</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://tintrongnguyen.me/fixed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Tin, a software engineer based in Saigon, Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love building software and products in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m bored, reading and writing are my options to escape reality. Like computers, right? I/O operations are the most common activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently work at &lt;a href=&#34;http://floatingcube.com&#34;&gt;Floating Cube Studios&lt;/a&gt;, also based in Saigon. We develop point of sale products and packages for small to middle size clients in Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t call myself a writer, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to fit in the writing habit.
There&amp;rsquo;s something about crafting sentences that lures me into creating this blog and start putting my thoughts online.
I personally think the choice of words is art.
Strangely, I can&amp;rsquo;t write in my mother tongue, yet, the feeling of cringing keeps striking me.
It&amp;rsquo;s something I definitely should work on, as this practice of literacy possibly be my main activity in the next 10 years.
And writing in English is not a good approach for a non-native speaker, in a country that doesn&amp;rsquo;t speak the language.
At the moment, I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying the freedom of burden and write whatever I want.
But in the long run, screenwriting is what I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a writer of any kind and located in Saigon, drop me a buzz and I buy you a drink! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/code/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://tintrongnguyen.me/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://tintrongnguyen.me/contact/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about removing this page. There are links to my &lt;em&gt;boring&lt;/em&gt; social life up there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>